原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供学习  禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻 译     Z小花儿        长尾电阻
翻 译     Lynn_宁        琦小果
翻 译     迷失_绽放      八步半
校 对     Santolalla
搞什么  系统崩溃了吗
Come on. Is the system down?
时间轴    海默应援浪     海默迷妹念想查
我这儿没问题
Worked fine for me.
我等不了了
I don't have time for this.
后 期     斯人
你怎么了
How you doing?
电脑故障了
The computer is not working.
我问的不是这个
That's not what I'm talking about.
知道  我没事
I know. I'm fine.
总 监     夕橙
有个病患因你的操作丧命
A patient died because of something you did.
我想你现在绝对不是「没事」
I think it's safe to say the one thing you are not is "Fine."
我在调整
I'm dealing.
你到底在怎么调整
How exactly are you dealing?
我在继续工作
I'm getting back to work,
要给糖尿病变脚趾做清创
I have a diabetic toe to debride,
我已经放下了
and I'm putting it behind me.
你是怎么做到放下的
How do you do that -- put it behind you?
往前看啊
By moving forward.
-谢谢你关心  -不用谢
- I appreciate your concern. - You're welcome.
我给你预约一次心理咨询吧
I'm gonna make an appointment for you for grief counseling.
莫翰医生  她很擅长给经历重压事件的
Dr. Mohan -- She's an expert in dealing with hospital staff
医务人员做心理疏导
who have experienced stressful events.
没必要
That's not necessary.
那你同意自己遭遇「重压事件」了吗
You agree you had a "Stressful event"?
虽然我很欣慰
And while I am comforted
你说已经放下过去往前看了
by your commitment to move forward by not looking back,
但还是希望你去见见莫翰医生
I still want you to see Dr. Mohan.
如果她说你没事了
If she says that you are fine,
只有那样  你才能重回手术台
then -- and only then -- can you go back to surgery.
系统现在好了
It's working now.
你得有耐心
You just have to be patient.
心率36
Heart rate 36.
再推十毫克吗啡  准备滴注硝酸甘油
Push another five milligrams of morphine and prep a nitro drip.
立刻准备阿托品
We need atropine on board stat.
什么情况
What do you got for me?
心肌梗塞并伴有严重心动过缓
An MI with severe bradycardia.
注射了阿司匹林和硝酸甘油
He's had aspirin, nitro,
现在打算给他注射实际量的阿托品
and now we're trying to give him a real rate with atropine.
心脏科医生看过了吗
Cardiology see him?
他的起搏器坏了
He's got a broken pacemaker
可能需要疏通他的冠状动脉
and probably needs his coronary arteries cleared --
应该要做三支冠状动脉分流术  但你才是专家
feels like a triple bypass, but you're the expert.
心衰定量标志物太高了
BNP is sky high.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
他的心室几乎不能泵血了
His ventricles are barely pumping.
有过两次严重的心肌梗塞
He's had two massive prior MIs.
心力衰竭末期
End stage heart failure.
他的心脏无法修复了
His heart's way beyond repair.
我们该怎么做
What are our options?
他已经73岁了
He's 73 years old.
这个年龄肯定没法获批做移植
His age is an absolute contraindication for transplant.
-他要死了  -至少现在还没死
- He's dying. - Well, he's not dead yet.
还有呢
What else?
心脏再同步化治疗如何
How about cardiac resynchronization?
让两边心室健康的部位能同步正常运行
That will get what's left of both ventricles working together.
用双心室起搏器
A biventricular pacer?
可以让他在剩下的几个月里好受一些
It should make him feel a little better in the few months he's got left.
心率再往下降  就会心脏骤停
His rate drops any lower, he'll arrest.
克莱尔  准备切开颈静脉安放临时起搏器
Claire, prep his jugular to float in a temporary pacemaker.
肖恩  通知导管室
Shaun, call up to the cath lab
让他们预估多久才能准备好
and have them get an estimate on how long it'll take
双心室起搏器
to get the bi-pacer in house.
有问题吗
Something wrong?
没有
Not at all.
只是早上咖啡喝多了
Just a little bit too much coffee this morning.
那继续  动手吧
Let's go. Do it now.
绑住他
Restraints, please!
我可不想被针头扎伤
I don't want to get stuck with a needle.
你们吓到他了
You're scaring him.
五毫克氟哌丁苯
Haldol, five milligrams.
你们吓到他了
You're scaring him!
-你是谁  -肖恩·莫菲医生
- Who are you? - Dr. Shaun Murphy.
这位病患有精神问题  莫菲医生
This patient is psychotic, Dr. Murphy.
他没有精神问题
He's not psychotic.
你不喜欢被别人碰
You don't like people touching you.
他没有精神问题  他有自闭症
He's not psychotic. He's autistic.
良     医
第一季  第七集
你是位非常配合的病患
You're being an excellent patient.
好了  弄完了
Okay. We're finished.
你跟我...
You're s-same as...
一样
me.
可以松开他的手吗
Can we release his hands?
莫菲医生  手能松开吗
Dr. Murphy? His hands?
我来了  孩子  爸爸妈妈来了
I'm here, son -- Mom and Dad are here.
你们可以松开他的手  他不会伤到你们
You can let go of his hands. He won't hurt you.
下错站了  下错站了
Wrong stop. Wrong stop.
谁能告诉我发生了什么
Can someone tell me what happened?
利亚姆的前额有5.4厘米的撕裂伤
Liam has a 5.4 centimeter laceration on his forehead,
可能是摔倒了
probably from a fall.
伤口用五毫升1%的利多卡因处理了
The wound was infiltrated with five milliliters of 1% lidocaine...
用5-0的普理灵缝线单点间断缝合了七针
7 -- 7 single-interrupted 5-0 Prolene sutures.
会留下小疤痕
He will have a small scar,
但伤口不会有其他长期影响
but no other long-term effects from this injury.
你是我儿子的主治医生
You're my son's doctor.
对  我是肖恩·莫菲  「恩赐」的「恩」
I am. Dr. Shaun Murphy -- "Shaun" with a U.
迷路了  迷路了  迷路了
Got lost -- got lost, got lost, got lost, got lost!
-对对  但你没事了  -迷路了  迷路了
- Yes, yes. Yes. But you're okay. - Got lost. Got lost, got lost.
以后不坐那趟公交了
You won't be taking that bus again.
灯光太亮了
This light is too bright.
这里让他很焦虑  我们能带他回家吗
These rooms make him anxious. Can we take him home?
不行
No.
你的儿子得黄疸了
Your son is jaundiced,
触摸和发热会让他的右腹肌肉紧张
clenching his right abdominal muscles when touched and febrile.
他不能回家
He should not go home.
我怎么在这
Why am I here?
你的起搏器故障了
Your pacemaker malfunctioned.
心脏病发作了
You had a heart attack.
我想我听得懂
I...I think I get that part.
你邻居的园丁看到你倒在屋里的地板上
Your neighbor's gardener saw you on the ground inside your house --
于是报警  救了你一命
called 911, saved your life.
那我得记着谢谢他
Well, I must remember to thank him.
你多大了
How old are you?
我吗
Me?
我知道我多大了
I know how old I am.
28岁
I'm 28.
我们给你准备了双心室起搏器
We have, uh, a biventricular pacer on its way,
会让你好受很多
and it's gonna make you feel a lot better.
是吗
Is it?
我一会儿回来给你准备手术
I will be back to prep you for surgery.
利亚姆的胆红素和肝酶都增高了
Liam has elevated bilirubin and liver enzymes,
白细胞23
a white cell count of 23.
腹部超声波结果显示胆管肿大
Abdominal ultrasound shows dilatation of the bile ducts.
似乎是上行性胆道炎
Sounds like ascending cholangitis --
如果细菌接触到血液  会引发败血症
can lead to sepsis if the bacteria gain access to his blood.
他现在情况稳定吗
Is he stable now?
他的生命体征稳定
Yes, his vital signs are stable.
原因从癌症到不良饮食都有可能  所以...
Cause could be anything from cancer to diet, so --
利亚姆的父母为他选择了生酮饮食
Liam's parents have him on a special ketogenic diet.
多用于治疗儿童难治性癫痫
高脂饮食可能会导致胆结石阻塞
High-fat diets can cause obstructive gallstones,
从而引发现在的症状
which could have set the whole thing off.
做个经内镜逆行性胰胆管造影术来查清楚
Do an ERCP to clear him.
之后用几周广谱抗生素
After that, a few weeks of broad spectrum antibiotics
应该就没问题了
should take care of things.
适应障碍筛查问卷
是否难以集中注意力
是否感到脱离人群
是否异常焦虑
是否因感到负担而压抑自己的感情
我需要你帮忙
I want you help.
什么事
With what?
经内镜逆行性胰胆管造影术
Endoscopic Retrograde Cholangio-Pancreatography.
ERCP  为什么
ERCP? Why?
你以前做过的  肖恩
You've done those before, Shaun.
你和自闭症患者相处得很好
You're good with people who have autism.
格伦  我们开始吧
Okay, Glen, let's get this, star...ted
格伦  你快好了吗
Glen, you almost finished?
我是卡卢医生
It's Dr. Kalu.
格伦
Glen?
我们需要全面封锁
Yeah, we have a code green.
患者为白人男性  84千克
Patient is Caucasian, male, 185 pounds.
肖恩  你能和他说说话吗
Shaun, can you talk to him or something?
我没法推咪唑安定
I can't push the Midazolam.
四盏灯  四扇门
Four lights...four doors.
没错  这有很多东西
Yes. Lots of things.
32, 8. 32, 8.
32是橱窗的数量
32 is the number of cabinet windows,
8是把手的数量
and 8 is the number of handles.
末端二氧化碳在上升
the end title's CO2 is rising.
他需要氧气  他出现呼吸抑制了
He needs oxygen. He has respiratory depression.
这是咪达安定的常见反应
It's a common reaction to Midazolam.
二氧化碳下降了
CO2 is coming down.
-你可以继续了  克莱尔  -  谢谢
-You can proceed, Claire. -Thank you.
你以前遇到过很多自闭症患者吗
Have you been around a lot of other autistic people?
从没遇到过
I've never met someone with autism.
那和利亚姆待一段时间挺不错吧
So, it must be nice to spend some time around Liam, then.
为什么
Why?
为什么会不错
Why would that be nice?
好吧
Okay.
没有结石
There are no stones.
结石在哪儿
Where are the stones?
这里有瘢痕
And there is scarring.
这和胆结石无关
This has nothing to do with gallstones.
整个胆管树都布满了瘢痕
The entire biliary tree is so thick with scarring
连内窥镜都伸不进去
we can't even get the camera through.
胆管瘢痕的诊断包括
The differential diagnosis for biliary tree scarring includes
原发性硬化性胆管炎  肝功能衰竭
primary sclerosing cholangitis, liver failure,
继发性原发性胆汁性肝硬化
secondary to primary biliary cirrhosis --
没错  肖恩  列表上还能加几种癌症
Yeah, Shaun, we can add a few cancers to that list as well --
列表真是又长又可怕
It's a long and ugly one.
想想其他方法来查明
Find another way to figure out what it is.
我们可以做核磁共振
We could do an MRI.
不  不行
No, we couldn't.
做不了
It's not possible.
我第一次听你这样说
That's the first time I've ever heard you say that.
-利亚姆有自我刺激行为  -自我刺激行为
-Liam is stimming. -Stimming?
抽搐和痉挛是神经应激反应
The tics and spasms are a neurological response to stress.
如果他做核磁共振  就会有压力
If he's doing an MRI, there is stress --
如果有压力  他就没法保持不动
if there is stress, he won't keep still,
如果他不能保持不动  我们就没法做核磁共振
if he wont' keep still, we can't do an MRI.
因此  做不了
Therefore, it is impossible.
如果你一直和他这样说话
Maybe if you just keep talking to him like that,
也许能让他睡着  一切就简单多了
he'll doze off and it'll all be simple.
给他低剂量镇静剂
Give him a mild sedative.
他做ERCP时对咪达安定反应不是很好
He didn't respond well to Midazolam during ERCP --
抑制了他的呼吸
depresses his breathing.
在里面没法准确监测他的呼吸饱和度
His respiratory saturation can't be properly monitored inside --
我明白了
I get it.
他可能死在核磁共振里面  而我们都不知道
He could die in the MRI and we wouldn't know.
你得想其他办法来安抚他
You're just gonna have to find a different way to calm him.
好的
Okay. We'll do it.
我猜他有主意了
Guess he has an idea.
现在进入全面封锁
We have a code green.
患者为白人男性  73岁
Patient is a Caucasian male, 73 years of age.
肖恩  你在干什么
Shaun, what are you doing?
计数
Counting.
-数什么  -距离
- Counting what? - Distance.
为什么
Why?
我想要1643块钱
I want $1,643.
数完你就有钱了吗
You can get that by counting?
所以你自己在这里步测吗
That's why you're alone and pacing in this room?
你想要钱干什么
What do you want the money for?
我想买个电视
I want to buy a television.
1600块钱的电视
$1,600 for a television?
还有43  我是个外科医生  我有薪水
And 43. I am a surgeon. I get paychecks.
你现在还不是外科医生  你是外科住院医师
You're not a surgeon yet. You're a surgical resident.
薪水还是差很多的  朋友
Ah, there's a big difference in the paycheck there, pal.
我不是小孩  朋友
I'm not a child, pal.
买个一千块的电视怎么样
How 'bout $1,000 for a television?
不  我想买那个1643块的电视
No. The one I want is $1,643, okay?
我知道  但是你有预算
I know, but you have a budget.
-预算  你... -房租  食物  账单
- A budget. You -- - Uh, rent, food, bills to pay.
我可以自己做预算  我得做核磁共振
I should do my own budget. I have an MRI to do.
这是入口  急救室  接收站的实时监控
These are live feeds -- entrances, E.R., receiving dock.
如果你的患者离开了  我们会看到的
If your patient had left, we would've seen it.
他能去哪儿
Then where'd he go?
货运电梯  但是里面没有监控
A freight elevator, but we don't have cams in the freights,
他没有出来
and he doesn't pop back up.
看来这是个外星绑架案了
So, we're dealing with an alien abduction here?
对不起
Sorry.
一  四  五层的货运电梯
We don't have cams on the freight elevators
和地下室都没有监控
on levels one, four and five, and the basement.
你找人去查看这些楼层了吗
And you got people looking on those floors?
我们已经搜查了四楼和五楼  正准备去一楼
We've covered four and five, and we're moving on to one.
格拉斯曼医生
和莫翰医生预约了中午12点的心理咨询
这是什么  大拇指吗
地下室有什么
What's in the basement?
儿科患者丢了个毯子
Pediatric patient lost a blanket --
我去失物招领看看
I'm just gonna check lost and found.
你人真好
That's nice of you.
趁你在这儿
While you're there,
也许你还能看看丢失的患者找到了没有
you might want to check if they found your code green.
我是医生...
This is Doctor...
我是肖恩
This is Shaun.
我可以听到你说话
I can hear you when you speak.
我在想些事情
I was thinking about something.
从救护车到急诊室要走24步
There are 24 steps from the ambulance to the E.R.
请把灯关上  有助于他恢复平静
Please turn down the lights. That helps calm him.
从救护车到急诊室要走24步
There are 24 steps from the ambulance to the E.R.
从救护车到急诊室要走22步
There are 22 steps from the ambulance to the E.R.
他步子很大
He has very long strides.
没错
Yes.
从救护车到急诊室要走22步
There are 22 steps from the ambulance to the E.R.
从电梯到405房间要走37步
There are 37 steps from the elevator to room 405.
从电梯到405房间
There are 37 steps
要走37步
from the elevator to room 405.
在405房间  走到水槽要六步
In room 405, there are 6 steps to the sink...
走到水槽要六步
6 steps to the sink.
我们得到了清晰的图像
We're getting good images.
对自闭症患者来说  你真了不起
It's amazing how accomplished you are for someone with ASD.
走到窗户要三步
Three steps to the window.
要三步
Three steps to --
三步
Three...
七步  走到门要七步
It's seven steps -- It's seven steps to the door.
利亚姆  走到门要七步
Liam, there are seven steps to the door.
你得把他弄出来
You need to get him out.
只要再等一会就好
Just a little more time.
他很害怕
He's scared.
害怕没关系  我们得做完
It's okay to be scared. We need to finish this.
-七步  -你做的很好  亲爱的
- Seven - You're doing wonderfully, honey.
呼吸就好  呼吸就好
Just breathe. Just breathe.
不  走到门要七步
No, it's seven steps to the door.
格伦
Glen?
我是卡卢医生
It's Dr. Kalu.
我带你上楼
Let's get you upstairs.
走开
Go away.
我会给你安装新的起搏器
We're gonna get your new pacer in.
你还不明白吗
Don't you get it?
我故意弄坏了自己的起搏器
I broke my pacer on purpose.
我想死
I want to die.
有了新的心脏起搏器  或许你会感觉好一些
With a new pacemaker, maybe you'll feel better.
所以  我可以痊愈
So, I'll be cured?
完好如初
Good as new?
它可以缓解你的痛苦  之后很有希望...
Well, it'll reduce your pain, and then hopefully --
你以为我是第一次听到这些陈词滥调吗
You think this is the first time I've heard that?
人们总说「退而求其次」
It's always the "Next best thing."
但事实是我一直在走下坡路
The truth is I'll just keep getting worse.
我心里清楚  你也是
I know it, you know it.
你有亲属可以谈谈吗
Do you have any family you can talk to?
我哥死了  我也没有妻子
Brother's dead. I don't have a wife.
所以我周围没有亲人可以唠叨我
So, no, there's no one around to nag me
劝我听你的话
into doing what you want.
我们这里提供很好的心理咨询服务
We have great counseling services here.
我一直非常痛苦  28岁的毛头小子
I'm in pain, 28 --
每时每刻
all the time.
你觉得谈话疗法能让痛苦消失吗
Talk therapy gonna talk that away?
让我带你上楼吧
Let's get you upstairs.
你脸色不太好  肺部有啰音
You color's not good, and your lungs are crackling,
这说明液体正在流向...
which means there's fluid building in --
我知道我的...
I know my...
我知道我享有哪些权利
I know my rights.
如果我不愿意  就不用非得接受治疗
I don't have to get treatment if I don't want it.
趁我还有一口气  我要离开这里
The minute I catch my breath, I'm gonna walk out of here,
所以你可以走了
so you can just leave.
我不会走
I'm not leaving.
我们找不到病因  就无法采取治疗
We can't treat it until we find the underlying cause.
你想怎么做
How do you do that?
通过手术  即「腹腔镜探查术」
Surgically -- It's called "Exploratory laparoscopy."
我们用相机来检查利亚姆的腹部
We use a camera to navigate Liam's midsection.
这种手术存在很大的风险
There are significant risks --
腹腔脏器穿孔
perforation of an organ,
意外造成肿瘤细胞扩散
accidental spread seeding malignancy.
而你必须得做这种手术
And you have to do this
因为他在做磁共振时不能保持静止
because he can't stay still during an MRI?
很显然你比我更了解你的儿子
You obviously know your son better than I do.
你觉得我们应该再试一次吗
Do you think we should try again?
肖恩说他要买台电视
So, Shaun told me he's getting a TV --
至少七十英寸
70 inches, all the works.
是吗
Is he now?
只是台电视而已
It's just a TV.
我担心的不是电视
It's not about a TV.
你为什么这么担心他
Why are you so worried about him?
他上班迟到了五六次
He showed up late for work half a dozen times,
他在凌晨两点钟给我打电话
he calls me 2:00 in the morning
就因为找不到螺丝刀
'cause he can't find a screwdriver,
而他的上司千方百计想把他赶出医院
and his superintendent wants to kick him out of his building.
-你去了吗  -什么
- Did you show up? - What?
凌晨两点他因为找不到螺丝刀
At 2:00 in the morning when he called you
而给你打电话时
about a lost screwdriver,
你去了吗
did you show up?
他急疯了  我不知道他会做出什么事
He was frantic. I didn't know what he was gonna do.
这里有47个住院医师
There are 47 residents here,
他们都会偶尔迟到
and all of them show up late sometimes,
他们都会犯错误
all of them make mistakes,
但好在  他们都能从中学到东西
and hopefully, all of them learn.
如果你想担心肖恩  没问题
If you want to worry about Shaun, fine.
但你费尽心力雇佣他
But you fought to hire him
是因为你知道他能在这学到东西
because you know he can learn.
问题是  你是否愿意放手让他去做
The question is, are you willing to let him?
肖恩
Shaun?
我可以看到像素点
I can see the pixelation.
-挺好的  听着  -这不好
- That's great. Listen. - It's not great.
这不好
It's not good.
在高清显示器上
On a high-quality display,
双眼1.2的视力根本看不到像素点
the human eye at 20/20 cannot detect the pixels.
磁共振检查失败以后你就不见了
You disappeared after the failed MRI.
我失败了
I failed.
是  可我觉得不是因为磁共振失败
Yeah, see, I don't think it's about that.
在那之前你就对这孩子犹豫不决
You were hesitant with this kid even before that.
你让我来做ERCP
You asked me to the ERCP.
医生不用非得喜欢他们的患者  克莱尔
Doctors don't have to like their patients, Claire.
-你不喜欢他  -我与他素不相识
- You don't like him? - I don't know him.
肖恩  这还有别的原因
Shaun, there's something else going on here.
-我知道你明白  -不  不  不
- I know you know that. - No. Nu-- Nu-huh.
他的情况和你一样
He has the same condition you have.
你之前还从未遇到过...
You have never met anyone with --
所有银屑病患者你都喜欢吗
Do you like all people with psoriasis?
我没有...
I don't have --
你有
Yes, you do.
而且你永远也治不好
And you can never get rid of it.
好吧
Okay.
你不喜欢他真是太遗憾了
It's too bad you don't like him,
因为我觉得他喜欢你
because I think he likes you.
不止如此  我觉得他崇拜你
Not only that, I think he looks up to you.
所以你知道他在想什么
So you know how he thinks?
可能没你知道得多
Well, not as much as you probably do.
你还在等什么
What are you waiting for?
等你昏倒
For you to pass out.
根据你脚踝的肿胀程度来看
Judging by the size your ankles...
应该用不了多久了
that shouldn't be too long from now.
希望我能在你死之前把你弄上楼
Then hopefully I can get you upstairs before you die.
你为什么要管我如何过自己的人生
Why do you give such a damn about what I do with my life?
我不知道  格伦
I don't know, Glen.
你为什么如此想结束生命
Why'd you want to die so bad?
我活够了
I've lived.
我有过得体的工作
I've had decent jobs,
我也失过业
and I've had jobs that went nowhere.
住过好房子
Had a good roof over my head,
也失去了好房子
and I've had that good roof taken away from me.
我爱过一个女孩  然后我结了婚
I loved a girl, and I got married.
度过我人生中最幸福的二十年
The 20 happiest years of my life...
然后她去世了
then she died.
现在我又孤身一人了
And now I'm alone
痛苦地活着
and in pain.
应该结束了
Feels like the end of the story.
我明白
I understand.
是吗
Yeah?
你也有过难熬的时候吗  毛头小子
You've had some tough times, too, 28?
没人理解你作为一个英俊的成功人士是何感受吗
Nobody understands what it's like to be so good-looking and successful?
我是被保姆和管家抚养大的
I was raised by nannies and housekeepers.
天呐
Oh, my God.
你是个混蛋
You're an ass.
你想说你经历的痛苦
Your point is you didn't suffer
不是因为你英俊聪明
because you were good-looking and smart --
而是因为你很有钱
you suffered because you were rich?
只有在圣诞节我才能见到我的父母
The only time I ever saw my parents was Christmas.
认真的吗  还要继续说
Seriously, the story continues?
他们每年都举行盛大的宴会
They had this big party every year,
不管他们走到哪里  都会为了宴会飞回来
and wherever they were traveling they'd always fly home for it.
我也必须回家
And I'd have to come home, too,
不论他们把我送到了哪个学校
from whatever school they sent me off to.
当我18岁的时候  我厌倦了这种生活
When I was 18, I decided that I was fed up.
我是一个男人  不想当他们的儿子了
I was a man, done being their son.
而且我准备公开告诉他们
And I was gonna tell them publicly,
告诉他们的朋友们他们有多可怕
tell all their friends what horrible people they were.
所以我从学校回到家  敲了敲门
So I came home from school, and I knocked on the door,
有人开了门
and someone answered.
但不是我的父母  是一个陌生人
But it wasn't my parents. It was a stranger.
没想到他们在数月前就卖掉了房子
Turns out they'd sold the house months ago.
他们走了
They were gone.
我猜他们也受够了我吧
I guess they were done with me, too.
为了给利亚姆准备腹腔镜检查
To prep Liam for the laparoscopy,
我们需要在他的胃里开四个小切口
we need to make four small incisions in his stomach.
我不需要做这个
I don't need to do it.
I-I don't need to do it.
-利亚姆  你需要做  -我不需要
- Liam, you do need to. - I don't need to!
只要坚持几秒钟就好  利亚姆
If you could just hold still for a second, Liam.
公车司机让我下车
The -- the bus driver lets me off.
我迷路了
I-I get lost --
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
我迷路了  我很饿
I get lost. I'm hungry.
我没法做饭
I can't make food.
没法洗澡  不需要做这个
C-C-Can't do bath -- Don't need to do it!
没法做饭  没法穿衣服
C-C-Can't do food -- C-Can't put on clothes.
没法坐公交车
Can't do bus.
我坐过公交车
I took the bus.
在错误的站台下了车
I got off at the wrong stop,
我很害怕  但接着我找到了方向
and I got scared, but then I found my way.
我做过一次核磁共振  让人受伤了
I did an MRI, and a man got hurt.
我犯了一个错误  我犯过很多错误
I made a mistake. I make a lot of mistakes.
你试着去走路
You tried to walk.
你犯了一个错误
You made a mistake.
但犯错是好事  你应该多犯一些错
But mistakes are good. You should make more.
你很像我
You're like me.
你有红眼  眼色素层炎
You have red eyes -- uveitis.
利亚姆吃维生素
Liam takes vitamins --
利亚姆也吃草药补充品吗
Does Liam also take herbal supplements?
卡瓦根  怎么了
Kava root. Why?
他不需要做腹腔镜手术
He doesn't need the laparoscopic surgery.
我知道他怎么了
I know what's wrong with him.
他的红眼  是由免疫系统冲突造成的
The red eyes -- they're caused by an immune flare-up,
也会产生我们在他的消化系统中看到的瘢痕
which can create the scarring that we're seeing in his digestive system.
治疗方案需要我们进入腹腔
The solution requires us to go in
一片片摘除掉肠道上的受损部位
and remove damaged segments of the bowel piece by piece.
你们
Us?
是的  我和我的团队
Yes, myself and my team.
莫菲医生在你的团队吗
Is Dr. Murphy on your team?
当然
Of course.
感谢你诊断我们的儿子
Thank you for diagnosing our son.
梅伦德斯医生  我们同意你做这个手术
Dr. Melendez, you have our permission to do the surgery,
但莫菲医生不能参与其中
but in no way will Dr. Murphy be in it.
患者的父母  他们不让步
Well, the parents -- they won't budge.
他们不信任患了自闭症的人
They don't believe that anyone who has autism
有能力进行手术
is capable do doing surgery.
很显然  他们很荒谬
Well, clearly they're irrational --
我说不好  肤浅的人们
I don't know -- shallow-minded people.
谁在乎他自不自闭  有什么区别吗
Who cares? What's the difference?
你同意他们的观点  对吗
You agree with them, right?
你同意他们吗
Do you agree with them?
这是我的团队  我不希望任何人来告诉我
It's my team -- I don't want anybody telling me
谁应该在我的团队里
who's supposed to be on my team,
即使是董事会
including the Board.
你没有回答我的问题
You're not answering my question.
这个问题没有意义
The question's moot.
没有意义  并不是
Moot? No, it's not.
如果你同意他们的观点
If you agree with them,
那么唯一的问题就是有人踩到了你的痛处
then the only issue is somebody stepping on your poor, little toes.
克服它  然后去救那个孩子
Get over it and go save the kid.
如果你不同意
If you don't agree,
如果你认为肖恩能够进行手术
if you think Shaun can handle surgery,
那就告诉他们
then tell them that.
让他们哪凉快去哪儿
Tell them to go screw themselves.
他们要么同意莫菲医生和你一起做手术
Either they agree that Dr. Murphy belongs in that room with you,
要么就去别的地方做手术
or you can go find them someplace else to do the surgery.
当时我18岁  举目无亲  身无分文
I was an 18-year-old with no one and no money.
所以我打三份工  然后贷了款
So I worked three jobs and took out loans.
还没死呢
Still alive.
故事不错  毛头小子
That's not a bad story, 28.
父母怎么样了
What happened with the parents?
现在我和他们有联系  但是...
I talk to them now, but...
帮我走到现在的人不是他们
they're not the people who got me here.
而是我从没想到的人
It was the people I didn't expect --
避难所的前海军给了我第一份工作
the ex-Marine at the shelter who got me my first job,
然后有个疯狂的艺术女孩
and this crazy artist girl
说服我去追求我的梦想
who convinced me to go after what I really wanted.
当你觉得孤身一人时  格伦
When you think you're alone, Glen,
其实你并不孤单
you're not.
好吧
All right.
「好吧」
All right?
准备好了吗
Ready?
二  三
Two, three!
没做不安的梦吗
No disturbing dreams?
我都值了36小时的班
After a 36-hour shift?
从我躺到床上那一刻
From the moment my head hits the pillow
到醒来那一刻
to the moment wake up,
一夜无梦
all I see is black.
你的注意力怎么样
How's your level of concentration?
有难以集中注意力吗
Have you had any difficulty focusing?
我可以一口气做完《纽约时报》的填字游戏
I mean, I can do the New York Times crossword puzzle in one sitting.
当然  有时我会希望自己更专注些
Sure, sometimes I wish I was more focused.
很正常吧
It's pretty normal, right?
肖恩与众不同
Shaun's different.
他也有学者综合征
He also has savant syndrome.
他记忆超群
He has a remarkable memory.
他有自闭症  跟我们的儿子一样
He has autism, same as our son --
同样的局限性
same limitations.
你也看到做核磁共振时我儿子的状态
You saw what happened to our son in the MRI --
他知道该安静地躺着  但他做不到
he knew he needed to lie still, but he couldn't.
要是莫菲医生在给我儿子动手术时
Now, what happens if Dr. Murphy breaks down like that
也像那样行为失控了呢
while he's standing over my son at an operating table?
你了解你的儿子
You know your son.
我了解外科医生
I know surgeons.
在跟莫菲医生共事之后
And after working with Dr. Murphy,
在手术台和其他地方质疑他之后
after challenging him in surgery and everywhere else --
或许他值得更多尊重
probably more than he deserved --
我可以说我对他信心十足
I can tell you he has my compete confidence.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们对他没信心
He doesn't have ours.
那我们现在怎么办
So, what do we do now?
我联系了圣约瑟夫的同事
I've contacted my colleague at St. Joseph's,
跟她介绍了利亚姆的情况
updated her on Liam's condition.
那里的医生很厉害
They have good people.
我们可以尽快安排转院
We can arrange for transportation as soon as possible.
我的手机在哪  看见我的手机了吗
Where's my phone? Have you seen my phone?
他的第二个包呢  装着他的药的
Where's his second bag, the one with his medications?
我想...
I want...
怎么了  宝贝
What, honey?
他说了我可以的
He said I could do it.
我想要肖恩医生
I want Dr. Shaun.
你的起搏器到了
Your pacemaker's here.
此刻已经在测试它了
The techs are programming it as we speak.
一旦准备好了  就给你装进去
The moment they're ready, we're gonna put it in.
我之前说我的妻子去世了
I told you my wife died.
事实是她抛弃了我
The truth is s-she left me.
但她抛弃我也情有可原
But I gave her good reason for that,
这是我该得的
so I got what I deserved.
-我们都... -但你没得到该得的
- We all make -- But you didn't get what you deserved --
你该有爱你的父母
good parents who loved you.
他们很幸运生了你  杰瑞德
They were lucky to have you, Jared.
你似乎调整得很好
You appear remarkably well-adjusted.
谢谢
Thank you.
那不是称赞
That's not a compliment.
我对此感到担忧
That's my concern.
我猜每个人的反应都不一样
Well, I assume everyone responds differently.
但每个人都有反应
The thing is everyone responds.
严格来说
Strictly speaking,
你还不需要接受治疗
you don't meet the criteria to be required to go into treatment
或者休假
or take a leave of absence,
所以我不会让你停职
so I'm not gonna ground you.
你是个坚强的女人  克莱尔
You're a strong woman, Claire,
而这个力量无疑帮助了你很多
and that strength has undoubtedly played a major role
让你走到今天
in getting you where you are.
但如果你对此事件压抑了自己的感情
But if you have suppressed feelings about this incident,
你需要说给别人听
you need to find someone to share them with.
否则  它们会吞噬你
Because if not, they will eat you up
不管你有多坚强
no matter how strong you are.
好  格伦  第二...
All right, Glen. Second ti--
拜托
Come on.
谢谢
Thank you.
这该是个非常有趣的手术
It should be a very interesting surgery.
我很高兴有机会参加
I'm glad I'm participating.
他的血压降到最低点
His pressure is bottoming out.
怎么回事
What's happening?
他肯定肠穿孔了
His bowel must have perforated.
他进入感染性休克
He's going into septic shock.
这个穿孔可能在任何地方
This perforation could be anywhere.
最快查看整条肠的最好方式是什么
What's the best way to access the entire bowel as quickly as possible?
全长中线切开
Full-length midline incision.
很好  标记一下
Good. Mark it.
我们切开之后要怎么做
And what do we do once we get in there?
取出整条肠
Eviscerate the entire bowel
以彻底检查坏死的部分
so we can check every inch for necrotic segments.
好  开始切开
Okay, let's make the cut.
你要不要负责切开
You gonna take it or not?
这是3L号手术刀
This is the Number 3 L.
高碳钢制成  不会折断
It's made of high carbon steel. It doesn't break.
没错  莫菲医生
That's correct, Dr. Murphy.
切开时间  下午2:05
Time of incision -- 2:05 p.m.
全面封锁
We have a code green --
患者为白人男性  73岁
patient is a Caucasian male, 73 years of age.
他去哪里了
Where'd he go?
好  我这就过去
Yeah, on my way.
我找到五公分长的近端空肠段
I have a five-centimeter segment of proximal jejunum.
已硬化  但没穿孔
It's...sclerotic, but not perforated.
好  标记然后继续
All right, mark it and move on.
肖恩  你为什么傻站着
Shaun, why are you just standing there?
我们还有八米的肠要查看
We have 25 feet of bowel to run.
肖恩  赶紧继续  除非你有发现
Shaun, you need to get moving -- unless you've found something.
-我找到穿孔了  -夹住它
- I have the perforation. - Clamp it off --
我会用肠切开剪去除受损部位
I'll get in there with the enterotomy scissors and remove the damaged segment.
我不能
I can't.
你不能  为什么
You can't? Why not?
是蜂窝织炎
It's a phlegmon.
你找到了透壁性脓肿
You found a walled-off abscess?
很大
It's large.
-别碰  -已经碰了
- Don't touch it. - I already am.
如果你移动造成它破裂
If you move and that thing ruptures,
脓会扩散到他整个腹腔
the pus will spread to his entire abdominal cavity --
造成死亡
this boy dies.
我知道  所以我没动
I know, that's why I'm not moving.
克莱尔  你把它轻轻地打开
Claire, I need you to open it up gently.
我要除去脓毒含量
I'm gonna evacuate the septic contents,
用抗生素冲洗腹腔
flush the cavity with antibiotics,
然后我会让你移除胶囊
and then I'm gonna have you remove the capsule.
我什么也没做
I didn't do anything.
血压在降到最低点
That's the pressure tanking.
必须赶快完成
You need to finish what you're doing right now.
赶紧  克莱尔  加油
Let's go, Claire. Come on.
夹住
Clamp.
你们去看左边
You guys check left.
起来吧
Come on.
住手
Stop.
好了  格伦
Come on, Glen.
我们能做到的
We can do this.
我不想...
I don't want to --
我就是不想
I just don't want to.
求你了  别管我
Please leave me alone.
我一有了力气  就爬起来跳下去
Once I get my strength back, I'll climb up and jump.
我不会让你那么做的
I can't let you do that.
当这个临时起搏器失效的时候
When this temporary pacer fails,
它肯定会失效的
which it will,
你的心跳就会停止  你会突然死亡
your heart may stop and you die suddenly.
但更有可能的是  格伦
But more likely, Glen,
你的心率会减缓
you slip back into that slow rhythm,
胸部剧痛
your chest is racked with excruciating pain
肺部开始充满液体
and your lungs start to fill with fluid,
你会缓慢窒息
and slowly you suffocate.
省省吧  毛头小子
Give it a rest, 28.
把不抢救预嘱拿来  再给我叫辆出租车就好了
Just get me a DNR and a cab.
你帮不了我的
You can't help me.
我可以
Yes, I can.
手术很艰难
It was a difficult procedure.
我们切除了...
We removed a total of two feet of --
他没事吧
Is he okay?
他会没事的
He will be okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
我  我很抱歉  我们  我们只是...
I-I'm sorry. We're -- We just...
他是我们的儿子
He's our son.
你们不用觉得抱歉
You shouldn't feel bad.
你们做了你们认为对于利亚姆来说最好的选择
You did what you thought was best for Liam.
你们爱利亚姆
You love Liam.
我就没有从我父母那里得到那样的爱
I didn't have that from my parents.
同时我也不用服用卡法根
It also means I didn't have to take kava root,
所以我没得嗜酸性胃肠炎
so I didn't get hypereosinophilic gastroenteritis.
你会因为这个而惹上麻烦吗
Are you gonna get in trouble for this?
你现在是在担心我吗
You're worried about me now?
你签署了不抢救预嘱
You signed the DNR.
我所做的只是坐在这里陪你
All I'm doing is sitting with you.
BGM: Kennedy by Donovan Woods
♪ When they say your father's name ♪
♪ They're talkin' 'bout a boat ♪
♪ They're not talkin' 'bout him ♪
♪ 'Cause they can't trust you as far ♪
你害怕吗
Are you feeling any anxiety?
不
No.
疼吗
Pain?
有点
Some.
要打一针吗啡来缓解一下吗
Would you like a dose of morphine to help with that?
♪ But back then the ship seemed sunk ♪
♪ I couldn't sleep when I wasn't drunk ♪
♪ But now a bad idea ♪
♪ Has cut you in two ♪
♪ Darlin', I just don't know ♪
谢谢
Thank you.
♪ Darlin', I just don't know ♪
♪ Some things you just let go ♪
BGM: Shine a Light by Banners
找到你的患者了
Find your guy?
找到了
I did.
做双室起搏器手术了
Put in the biventricular?
♪ Light will lead the way to set you free ♪
到冠状窦要多久
How long did it take to get access to the coronary sinus?
♪ I'm only looking for a little peace ♪
我没有做手术
I didn't do the surgery.
我没有把起搏器放进去  他...
I didn't put the pacer in. He, um...
他不想做
he didn't want it.
他是个好人
He was a good guy.
♪ And when the night falls ♪
♪ Oh, call on me ♪
♪ Just don't forget to show me some mercy ♪
我也失去了一位患者
I lost a patient, too.
想聊聊吗
Want to talk about it?
♪ Say you're mine ♪
想
I do.
♪ Take me higher ♪
你的手术很成功
Your surgery went well.
我们一旦确认抗生素清除了感染
You should be able to get up and move around in two weeks
你就能起来走动了  时间约为两周
once we're sure the antibiotics have cleared your infection.
听到了吗
Hear that?
我们很快就能回家了
It won't be too long until we can go home.
你做得很棒  宝贝
You did great, honey.
灯光
The lights.
♪ Shine a light ♪
这个亮度可以吗
Are the lights okay?
♪ Shine a light on me ♪
还是想暗一些
Do you want them dimmed?
♪ Shine a light on, shine a light on me ♪
这样...  就可以了
They're...okay.
♪ 'Cause I was lost at sea ♪
♪ While the waves were dragging me underneath ♪
♪ Shine a light on, shine a light on me ♪
你一定会爱上那个软件的
You'll love the software.
它让做预算变得很容易
It makes it very easy to budget.
最棒的是  它直接关联到银行
And the best part, it links directly to the bank,
放开球
and -- get rid of the ball!
他是2013年在第一顺位被选中的四分卫
He was the first quarterback picked in 2013,
但据说他的传球成功率只有27％
but his stats outside the pocket are only 27% competed passes.
他们的替补四分卫在压力下的传球成功率为65％
Their backup QB is at 65% under pressure.
是啊
Absolutely.
-做替补真是浪费了他的天赋  -是啊
- He's wasted potential on the bench. - Yes.
总之  和银行的关联会帮助自动...
Anyway, the link to the bank will help make automatic --
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
他按住了他的头盔  甚至都犯规了
He pinned it against his helmet -- even with the PI!
我要去看超级碗
I want to go to the Super Bowl.
好了  看  这就是那种
Okay, see, that's exactly the kind of thing
你在买之前得考虑一下的事情
you have to think about before you buy.
票很贵的
Tickets are very expensive.
你知道...你知道吗  你应该去
You know -- You know what? You should go.
我也应该去  我们都应该去
I should go. We should go.
好
Okay.
不好意思
Excuse me.
马上就要关门了  所以...
It's almost closing time, so...
我想买这台电视
I'd like to buy this TV.
你们想待多久都行
Stay as long as you like.